VALIA LIU (CHENCHENG)

+1 (401)-263-1925 | cliu07@risd.edu valiaaa.github.io/cocoonstorage/

A Providence / Shanghai based graphic designer who does a variety of design works. I am keen to gain more professional experiences, especially within the field of publication and digital communication, and explore things that I am not yet familiar with. Beside my design work, I made a variety of handcraft pieces, like jewelry, sewing, knitting, and embroidery, which often become the inspirations of my design works.

SKILLS

- Layout / Typesetting
- · Visual Identity / Branding
- Visual Coding
- · Motion Graphic
- 3D Modeling
- Video Editing / Animation
- Printmaking

TOOLS

2D Design

- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- Indesign
- Lightroom
- Figma

3D Design

· Cinema 4D

Motion Design

- Premiere
- · Final Cut Pro
- · Basic After Effects

Others

- HTML / CSS
- Microsoft Office
- Procreate

EDUCATION

Rhode Island School of Design | Sep 2019 – May 2023 | Providence, RI BFA Graphic Design

Honor Student for: Fall 2020, Spring 2021, Spring 2022

CREATIVE EXPERIENCES

Freelance | Sep 2016 - Current (6 years) Graphic Designer / Artist

- · Customize design, illustration, and handcrafts to more than 150 customers.
- Design yearbook cover for the class of 2019 of Shanghai Pinghe Bilingual School highschool department.
- Set visual system, poster series, and signature boards for multiple school size activities like annual parties, halloween parties, and proms.
- Design logo and a set of team-uniforms for a highschool frisbee team.
- Illustrate stop-motion opening and ending, banner, and avatar for a Youtube channel named "MicroNova".
- · Design album covers for music artist, Harry Kang.

Shanghai Symphony Orchestra | Jan 2019 – Feb 2019 | Shanghai, China Designer Assistant

- Research the references for exhibition arrangement and side-line products.
- Measure the scale of the exhibition space, and finish the first edition of the artwork arrangement.
- Design several visual possiblities for the side-line products, and finish four versions of design in two kinds of visual style.
- · Modify posters of the upcoming orchestra performances.

Shiyuan Consulting Co.,Ltd | Apr 2019 – Jun 2019 | Shanghai, China Graphic Designer

- Design 5 posters for group activities of museum exhibitions.
- · Create visual layouts on social media.

OTHER EXPERIENCES

Rhode Island School of Design | Feb 2022 – May 2022, Sep 2022 – Dec 2022 RISO Printing Monitor | Providence, RI

- Communicate with students from a varied of majors, helping them to set the correct form of file for printing, and recommending the suitable printing options to their pieces.
- Set up every step for the printing manually, like change the ink chunk.

Rhode Island School of Design | Sep 2022 – Dec 2022 | Providence, RI Teaching Assistant for Design Studio 3

- Guide the junior graphic design majored students to build and refine their works conceptually and formly.
- Contribute on the structure of the class from a student's point of view during regular meeting with professors.

Rosso Fashion and Arts Education | Jul 2021 | Shanghai, China Teaching Assistant

- Document the key elements introduced in the courses and instructing student works.
- Record the performance and process of the students, and communicate with their guardians.



valia.cargo.site Providence, RI / Shanghai



Dear Ms. Izabelle,

My name is Chencheng Liu and I go by Valia. I am a rising senior graphic design student at Rhode Island School of Design. With multiple professional design experiences in the past, I would like to join the design team of Zocdoc as an intern with plenty of visual-based skills and the enthusiasm to improve myself as a professional graphic designer.

Communicating with both internal and external contributors is something that I am pretty confident about. Mostly, I worked as a freelance artist/designer before and have collaborated with over 130 clients so far. This experience makes me fluent in learning my customer's demands and feedback. At the same time, my teamwork experiences trained me to brainstorm conceptual ideas and possible visual treatments, finely finish the distributed work, critique each other's pieces, and refine the design based on peer feedback. Also, I worked as a team on a site-specific project in my studio class, as well as several collaborative zine projects. In most cases, I was in charge of setting the overall visual system and composing the final presentation. These helped me to improve my project management skill and leadership experiences.

In addition, aside from the capacity to use the Adobe creative suite, I'm also capable of using 3d modeling applications, like Cinema 4D, to broaden the visual potential of my works. Moreover, I've done several videos or motion graphics because they are the current visual trends. Besides the 10-min documentary film that I produced independently, I also created several illustration-based stop motion animation pieces with different directions, like narrative, promotional, and commercial. Furthermore, I'm currently studying web-based visual programming so that I can make better use of the website as an essential medium.

I would like to have the opportunity to meet with you and discuss the internship opportunity you have available. Please feel free to reach out to me through email at cliu07@risd.edu.

Thank you for your time and consideration!

Sincerely, Valia